Ben Keegan

Software Engineer

Resilient and creative software engineer with over 2 years of experience designing, building, and deploying full-stack applications for web and mobile. Able to take ownership, adapt quickly to new technologies, and actively make critical product and design decisions. Seeking a role at a fast-paced company with a highly collaborative working environment, where I can work with other passionate and talented engineers and contribute to impactful work from day one.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Co-Founder, Full Stack Software Engineer

Feb 2021 - Nov 2022

Pathbreaker - San Francisco, CA

- Co-founded and successfully drove application from idea to production, connecting 3000+ travelers in 80+ countries
- Developed, implemented, and maintained system design for social travel-mapping platform:
 - o Constructed relational database for persistent data storage
 - Created backend API service to allow authenticated users to build their profiles and create informational travel "paths"
 - o Designed UI/UX, built, and deployed client applications for web, iOS, Android
- Created CI/CD pipeline with Github Actions, optimizing development speed by automating testing and deployment processes
- Directed recruitment efforts, carrying out interviews, hiring, and managing contracted engineers, improving speed of development

Technologies leveraged: Javascript/Typescript, React/React Native, Mapbox, Python Flask, SQLAlchemy, Firebase, Cloudflare, Digital Ocean

Software Engineer (Intern)

May 2020 - Nov 2020

Cydoc - Durham, NC / Remote

- Created "Invite Friends" feature for sending automated email campaigns building a new channel for user acquisition
- Designed and built "Contact Us" page by introducing Firebase database to optimize management of user feedback
- Developed auto-load functionality for streamlining integration of past medical note information, improving speed at which doctors could complete notes
- Presented progress and contributed feature ideas during weekly Zoom stand-ups

Technologies leveraged: Javascript, React, Context, Python, Flask, CSS, Firebase, Twilio Sendgrid

Software Engineer (Intern)

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

Eightfold.ai - Mountain View, CA

- Optimized experience of ingesting customer data dumps into the Eightfold system by designing and building improved UI for internal Data Extract Ingest tool
- Led migration of internal configurations editor from legacy Jinja/jQuery to upgraded implementation using React
- Developed and presented novel product idea in customer hackathon

Technologies leveraged: Javascript, React, Redux, Python, Flask, jQuery, Jinja

PROJECTS

Personal Portfolio Site - benkeegan.vercel.app

Designed and built personal portfolio site showcasing skills, work experience, projects, and contact details - built w/ Typescript, React, Next.js, Styled Components, and Vercel

Spotemy

Designed and built web app for visualizing personalized Spotify data and generating music recommendations with OpenAI, built w/ React, Typescript, Next.js, Styled Components, Vercel

gRPC Image Processing Service

Designed, built, and wrote test suite for command line Python gRPC service for processing images pixel by pixel, applying rotations and/or filters

Duke Marketplace Web Application

Designed and built React client for student marketplace web app, integrating Stripe API for payments and Cloudflare for image upload and hosting. Designed relational database which effectively stored mock data for 15,000+ users and 20,000+ listings

EDUCATION

Duke University

Bachelor of Science
Major in Computer Science
Certificate in Innovation &
Entrepreneurship

Durham, NC — Aug 2017 - May 2021

Robertson Scholar in Robertson Scholars Leadership Program Relevant Coursework: Advanced Software Design and Implementation, Data Structures and Algorithms, Rapid Software Prototyping, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Architecture, Design & Analysis of Algorithms, Database Systems

SKILLS

Languages:

- Javascript/Typescript (Advanced)
- Python (Advanced)
- Java (Intermediate)
- GraphQL (Intermediate)
- **SQL** (Intermediate)
- **C** (Intermediate)
- HTML/CSS (Intermediate)

Frontend^a

- React/React Native (Advanced)
- Redux/React Context (Advanced)
- **Next.js** (Intermediate)
- **UI/UX Design** (Intermediate)

Backend:

- Flask (Advanced)
- **Django** (Intermediate)
- Node.js (Intermediate)
- **gRPC** (Intermediate)
- Relational Database Design

Tools:

- **Git** (Advanced)
- Docker (Intermediate)
- Xcode (Intermediate)
- Google Firebase (Intermediate)

CONTACT

San Francisco, CA

(919) 519-6575 ben.keegan98@gmail.com

benkeegan.vercel.app linkedin.com/in/benkeegan98 github.com/benkeegan98